Notice that while we calculated our returns for one particular portfolio,
注意 虽然我们计算了某个特定投资组合的收益率
if we chose different stocks,
但是如果我们选择其他股票
we could create another portfolio to represent the size factor.
我们可以创建另一个代表市值因子的投资组合
If we decided to buy in short twice as much,
如果我们决定做多和做空两倍
this could potentially be another portfolio representing the size factor.
可能会形成代表市值因子的另一个投资组合
How do we generalize this to other portfolios that
如何泛化到其他买入小盘股
buy small-cap stocks in short large-cap stocks?
并卖出大盘股的投资组合？
Well, rather than trying to create an infinite number of long-short portfolios,
与其尝试创建无限个做多-做空投资组合
we can use a single standard portfolio and then see how other portfolios co-vary with it.
我们可以使用一个标准投资组合 然后看看其他投资组合如何与其一起变动
In other words, portfolios that are just like the standard portfolio
换句话说 像标准投资组合的投资组合
would move up or down in the same percent as the standard portfolio.
会以相同的百分比与标准投资组合一起上下波动
Some other portfolio that may not have such an extreme bet on
其他对股票市值没有如此极端假设的投资组合
the market cap of stocks may move a fraction as much as the standard portfolio.
可能会以一定的比例与标准投资组合一起变化
In fact, we don't have to limit ourselves to portfolios.
实际上 不用仅限于投资组合
We could check to see how much a single stock moves
我们可以检查单个股票
in relation to this long-short portfolio.
相对于此做多-做空投资组合变化多少
If we perform the regression in which the independent variable was
如果进行回归的话 自变量是市值投资组合的收益率
the return of this size portfolio and the stock return was the dependent variable,
因变量是股票收益率
then the beta coefficient of that regression would give us a measure of how
那么这个 β 系数可以告诉我们
exposed the stock is to the movements of this size-based portfolio.
股票对此市值投资组合的变化的暴露度是多少
Let's look at what Fama and French did to create the size factor.
我们看看 Fama 和 French 是如何创建市值因子的
Start with an estimation universe,
首先是一个估测股票池
which is a set of stocks that are representative of a region or countries stock market.
其中包含一组能代表某个国家/地区股市的股票
Sort the stocks by market cap.
按照市值对股票排序
The top 90 percent by market cap are put into a portfolio called "Big".
市值在前 10% 的股票放入“大盘股”投资组合中
The bottom 10 percent by market cap are put into a portfolio called "Small".
最后的 10% 放入“小盘股”投资组合中
Calculate the equal weighted return of the Small portfolio,
计算小盘股投资组合的同等加权收益率
and the equal weighted return of the Big portfolio,
以及大盘股投资组合的同等加权收益率
then take the difference,
然后计算二者之差
the return of small minus the return of big.
即小盘股的收益率减去大盘股的收益率
This difference gives us a measure of
这个差异可以衡量
the return that can be attributed to investing based
根据小盘股往往会跑赢大盘股
on the hypothesis that small-cap stocks tend to outperform large-cap stocks.
这个假设投资后带来的收益率
We can think of this in terms of a long-short portfolio which buys
可以将其看作做多-做空投资组合
the small cap stocks and shorts and equal dollar amount of the large-cap stocks.
即买入小盘股并做空同等金额的大盘股
The daily returns of this long-short portfolio
这个做多-做空投资组合的每日收益率
are the factor returns of this size factor.
就是市值因子的因子收益率
So, we now have a factor time series that we can use in a factor model.
现在我们获得了可以用在因子模型中的因子时间序列
Note that in the Fama-French notation,
注意 在 Fama-French 公式中
this size factor is written with the acronym SMB.
这个市值因子用缩写 SMB 表示
Can you guess what that stands for?
你知道它的全称吗？
SMB stands for Small Minus Big.
SMB 是 Small Minus Big 的全称